Vivian Chen

vivianc206@gmail.com | https://chenvivian.github.io/ | www.linkedin.com/in/chenviv

SUMMARY

Data analyst with 3+ years of experience in creating and aggregating data, generating visualizations, and writing documentation. Strong interest in understanding how data can be used to tackle everyday challenges from the person to city level. Seeking full time fall opportunities to apply and enhance data mining and programming skills to create solutions for real-life applications, urban issues, and company efficiency.

EDUCATION

NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress

New York, NY

Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics

08/2019 - 07/2020

Capstone Project: A Data-Driven Approach to Preserving NYC Nightlife Cultural Spaces

Macaulay Honors College at Hunter College (CUNY)

New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts in Geographical Information Science

08/2015 - 06/2019

Minors in Computer Science and Media Studies

Member of Gamma Theta Upsilon (2019)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• GIS Software ArcMap, ArcGIS Pro, QGIS

Languages, Database Tools
Python, SQL, JavaScript, Microsoft Access, HDFS, Hadoop, Apache Spark

Design/Data Visualization
Tableau, D3.js, MapBox, Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator), AutoCAD Map 3D

WORK EXPERIENCE

Citymapper 06/2020 - Present

City Operations Data Analyst

• Researching and curating 10+ U.S. cities' public transportation data (GTFS, GBFS) for weekly app updates using Git, Python, and OpenStreetMap

New York City Economic Development Corporation

01/2020 - 05/2020

Transportation Intern (Planning Department)

- Analyzed residents' MTA travel patterns through predicting trip origin and destinations by using publicly available data, Python, and Excel
- Standardized bathymetry data and spearheaded GIS database creation for NYC waterfronts under NYCEDC jurisdiction using ArcMap and AutoCAD
- Conducted social media research surrounding COVID-19 impacts on the food and trucking industry

New York City Department of Transportation

GIS College Aide (Asset Management Unit)

03/2018 - 02/2020

- Built and maintained geodatabases through customized scripts using Python, SQL, and VBA
- Created and updated maps and metadata of NYCDOT assets through ArcMap, ArcCatalog, and QGIS
- Generated dashboards using MS Excel and MS Access for data visualization and projection analysis
- Through MS Access, designed a database to track seating arrangements for all DOT floors within the 55 Water St. building to streamline the agency's emergency preparedness procedures

Barnard College, Empirical Reasoning Center

08/2019 - 12/2019

Teaching Assistant (Intro to GIS Methods)

Supported Prof. Alisa Rod by guiding students on using GIS, grading labs, and holding weekly office hours

HONORS AND AWARDS

NYU CUSP Academic Scholarship

2019 - 2020

William E. Macaulay Scholarship

2015 - 2019